I disk fired our bowl, I'm going to take it out, now it's nice and hard.
But it's still very porous.
This is in the best shape for us to glaze our pot because the glaze is going to soak in there.
But before we do that we want to wax our foot ring right here.
We call it a foot because it sits on there, right?
We're going to take some liquid wax, some cool stuff.
We're going to start right in the center smear it around like this, if you get to much on there as you tip it, which we don't want to do, as we tip it wax rolls off runs down the side glaze won't stick to there.
Since it didn't do that we still have some wax in our sponge so I'm going to go about a quarter of an inch at least slowly turn the pot turning my wrist, both wrists like that all the way over.
Now we have a nice wax.
I don't know if you can see that?
We've got a nice wax ring around there.
That's good, I'm going to turn my pot.
Instead of starting where I left off I'm going to come back here, I'm going to get more wax so you can see, I'm going to come back here where I started, and pick that line up so I have a nice clean line, come all the way over in here.
That hole in there is so I can hang it up on the wall, by the way.
There, we've waxed our bowl, we're going to set it upside down like that.
Only takes a few minutes for it to dry.